# Abirami Anandaraj

#### **Associate Consultant**

HR Consultant with full cycle recruiting and coordinating experience in IT Staffing. Communicates and collaborates effectively with both candidates and clients by relying on Industry knowledge and interpersonal skills. Maintains a positive attitude under pressure and is naturally adaptable at building relationships at all levels. I am willing to work and learn more in HR Operations/Practices, Compensation, Benefits and Vendor Management areas.



(+91)8870209286 / 7339656106



abiramianandaraj@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/abir ami-anandaraj-0b99b0142/

### **Education**

Master's in Business Administration

Bannari Amman Institute of Technology 09/2019 - 04/2021 CGPA - 8.6

## Bachelor of Engineering

Sathyabama Institute of Science and Technology 07/2015 - 07/2019

## **Technical Skills Worked**

- Microsoft Technologies .NET, C#.NET, ASP.NET
- Web Technologies Java, ReactJS, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Python, Ruby on Rails, Golang, PostgreSQL
- Mobile Technologies Android and IOS
- 4. Testing Manual and Automation testing

# Work Experience

**Associate Consultant** 

Careernet Technologies 05/2021 - Present

- Handling End to end recruitment on Pan India (Permanent and Contractual Positions).
- Responsible for full lifecycle of Recruitment (Sourcing, Short-listing, Interviewing, arranging client Interview and closing).
  Taking up the complete ownership of the candidate.
- Posting Job Ads on various recruitment in Job portal, social media and Professional networks
- Recruiting candidates through portals, candidates' references, networking and internal databases. Scrutinizing resumes as per the requirements of the clients.
- Conducting initial level telephonic discussion and briefing the candidates about the job description and organization profile.
- Arranged and handled the Walkin interviews in client places.
- Conducting online tests and explaining the test content for the shortlisted candidates.
- Managed the overall interviews, selection and closing the positions. Ensure all screening, hiring and selection is done in accordance with employment law and regulations.
- Trained, coached and mentored consultants to increase team productivity.

# Clients and their requirements Supported

- 1. Gogo Air Senior Software Engineer (Backend and Frontend), DevOps Engineer
- Fourkites Staff Engineer, Full Stack developer, Senior Software Engineer (Backend and Frontend)

- 3. ViaSat- Software Engineer (Backend and Frontend), Full Stack developer
- 4. Netradyne- Software Engineer, Full Stack developer
- 5. Reliance Jio Software Engineer (Backend and Frontend)
- 6. KLA- Technical Lead
- 7. Yubi Senior Software Engineer (Backend and Frontend)
- 8. Tekion- Senior software engineer
- 9. Interface.ai QA Lead, Senior Software Engineer
- 10. Comcast- Automation Testing, ETL Testing, Software Engineer, QA
- 11. PhonePe- Senior Software Engineer, IOS Developer, Android developer, Principal Software Engineer, React Native, SDET
- 12. OEConnections- Software Engineer (Java, PHP, .NET), .NET Developer, Technical Lead, Application Manager
- 13. Socure- DevOps Engineer
- 14. Cleartrip- Senior DevOps, Android developer, Senior Software Engineer
- 15. Appviewx Engineer Software Development
- 16. ServiceNow-Staff Product Designer
- 17. Metayb- SAP MM, SAP FICO, SAP SD, SAP ABAP
- 18. Logitech- Firmware Engineer, Senior Firmware Engineer, Senior Electrical Engineer
- 19. Cure.Fit- Manual Testing
- 20. Opendoor- Senior Software Engineer (Backend), Full Stack Developer
- 21. Toyota-Full Stack Developer, Software Engineer (Frontend)
- 22. Syscloud- Database Administration
- 23. Orocorp Software Engineer (backend), Full Stack Developer

## **Talent Acquisition Intern**

#### **Arvind Internet**

09/2020 - 02/2021

- Partnering with hiring managers to determine staffing needs.
- Screening resumes.
- Performing in-person and phone interviews with candidates.
- Administering appropriate company assessments.
- Performing reference and background checks.
- Making recommendations to company hiring managers.
- Coordinating interviews with the hiring managers.
- Following up with the interview process.
- Maintaining relationships with both internal and external clients to ensure staffing goals are achieved.
- Communicating employer information and benefits during the screening process.